Guide to the James Boyd Collection of New York City Etchings 1861-1940, undated (bulk, 1910-1939) PR 7
New-York Historical Society
- Series I: New York City Etchings
  - Nankivell, Edith (1896-1984)
    - Seventh Ave & 62nd looking east [from Central Park] (243), 1926 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 44)
    - Washington Irving's House (second state) (244) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 44)
    - Washington Irving's House (245) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 44)
    - Society Library - University Place between 12th and 13th Streets (246), 1934 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 44)
    - Sunday Concert at the Metropolitan Opera House (301) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 44)
    - From Central Park (302), 1923 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 44)
    - The Collegiate Church of St. Nicholas (304), 1930 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 44)
    - President Monroe's Old Home at Prince and Lafayette Streets (306), 1925 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 44)
    - Zeta Psi House, New York University, University Heights (307) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 44)
    - Christmas Greetings from Edith Nankivell [Washington Arch] (308), 1925 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 44)
    - Hudson River and 139th Street (355), 1924 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 45)
    - [Woolworth Building from Municipal Building entrance] (359) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 45)
    - From Central Park No. II (382) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 45)
    - Jefferson Market (405), colored etching (Offsite-box 3, Folder 45)
    - Old 40th Street Houses (407), 1925 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 45)
    - The Planter's Hotel [Washington & Albany streets] (408) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 45)
    - Nocturne No. I [12th St and 4th Ave.] (409), 1922 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 45)
    - The New York [Public] Library, Fifth Avenue (410), 1931 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 45)
    - Bryant Park (411) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 45)
    - Quaker Meeting House on Gramercy Park (431) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 45)
    - Old 40th Street Houses [from cancelled plate] (465), 1923 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 45)
    - Woolworth Building (466), 1935 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 45)
    - Woolworth Building [1st state] (467), 1935 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 45)
    - Eternal Light, Madison Square (478), 1937 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 46)
    - George Washington Bridge (479), 1937 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 46)
    - Manhattan from Governors Island (480), 1936 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 46)
    - New York from Governors Island (481), 1936 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 46)
    - Class of 1882 Library Fund, New York University (482) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 46)
    - City Hall (483) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 46)
    - Britton Cottage, Staten Island (487), 1939 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 46)
    - Triborough Bridge (488), 1939 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 46)
    - Bryant Park (489), 1939 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 46)
    - Hell Gate (490), 1939 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 46)
    - Little Church Around the Corner (497), 1941 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 46)
    - St. Patrick's Cathedral [from Radio City] (498) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 46)
    - St. Andrew's Church, Staten Island (499) (Offsite-box 3, Folder 46)
  - Nankivell, Frank A.
    - Oyster Market - W. 13th St. & Hudson River (468), 1912 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 47)
    - Victory Arch (469), 1919 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 47)
      See: Box 6, Folder 95
  - Nordfeldt, Bror Julius Olsson (1878-1955)
    - [St. Thomas Church] (363), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 48)
    - St. Paul's Chapel (364), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 48)
    - [St. Patrick's Cathedral] (365), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 48)
    - [Madison Square Garden] (366), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 48)
    - Washington Arch (367), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 48)
  - Pennell, Joseph (1866-1922)
    - St. Paul's New York (291), 1915 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 49)
    - Among the Skyscrapers (292), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 49)
  - Quinlan, Will J. (1877-1963)
    - [Junction 6th and 9th Ave. el lines, Greenwich St.] (320), 1924 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 50)
    - The New York Public Library [Fifth Ave.] (321), 1912 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 50)
    - [Van Cortlandt Manor] (322), 1906 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 50)
    - Cortlandt Street (323), 1921 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 50)
    - [Washington Bridge/Harlem River along Speedway] (350), 1909 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 50)
    - Under the Brooklyn Bridge [East River] (351), 1910 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 50)
    - Varick St. N.Y. City [St. John's Chapel] (436), 1916 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 50)
    - Brooklyn Bridge from James Slip (437), 1910 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 50)
    - Metropolitan Life and Madison Square Towers (438), 1908 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 50)
  - Rainsford, K.
    - [Plaza Towers from Central Park] (325), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 51)
    - [Heckscher Building, Vanderbilt Mansion and Fountain] (326), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 51)
    - [City Hall and Municipal Building] (337), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 51)
    - [Riding Club of New York, 7 East 58th St.] (338), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 51)
    - [Battery Place] (424), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 51)
    - [Governors Island fortifications, Manhattan skyline] (426), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 51)
    - [East River shoreline, looking north from 59th St.] (446), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 51)
  - Reimer[or Rieppel?], Ludwig I.
    - New York Towers from Brooklyn Bridge, aquatint (207), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 52)
    - New York - the Battery, colored etching (208), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 52)
  - Reindel, William George (1871-1948)
    - [New York Public Library, Fifth Avenue] (425), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 53)
  - Roth, Ernest D. (1879-1964)
    - New York from Brooklyn Heights (1), 1918 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 54)
    - St. Paul's N.Y. City (3), 1918 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 54)
    - Madison Square (6), 1918 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 54)
    - The Riverside Church (29), 1930 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 54)
    - Roosevelt House, 18 E. 20th St., New York City (43), 1923 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 54)
    - Old Houses on Seventh Ave. (bet. 18th & 19th streets) (335), 1918 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 54)
    - My Neighbor's Yard (146th Street & Park Ave., Bronx) (378), 1916 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 54)
    - Riverside Church (proof from destroyed plate) (451), 1930 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 55)
    - Towers, Tugs & Barges, Downtown New York (452), 1935 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 55)
    - Downtown New York - Financial Towers (453), 1935 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 55)
    - Library of Columbia University (454), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 55)
    - Queensboro Bridge - Manhattan from Welfare Island (455), 1935 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 55)
    - New York from Brooklyn Heights in 1923 (456), 1934 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 55)
    - Coenties Slip - Downtown NY (457), 1935 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 55)
  - Rudinoff, W.
    - [Harbor scene, New York] (177), 1913 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 56)
    - New York Harbor #18 (178), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 56)
    - New York Harbor #5 (179), undated (Offsite-box 3, Folder 56)
  - Ruzicka, Rudolf
    - [University Club - 1 West 54th St.], wood engraving (249), 1928 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 57)
    - [St. John's Chapel, 46 Varick St.] (361), 1911 (Offsite-box 3, Folder 57)
  - Schmidt, Louis
    - Baptist Church, 563 Park Ave [later] Central Pres. Church (86), 1929 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 58)
    - Queensborough Bridge - from 55th Street and Avenue A (140), 1929 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 58)
    - South Street and Coenties Slip (333), 1929 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 58)
    - Bridge of the New York Connecting Railroad, looking N.E. from 67th St. (362), 1929 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 58)
    - Fulton Fish Market - South St. (420), 1929 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 58)
  - Schutz, Anton (1894-1977)
    - [The New Gateway to Wall Street] Irving Trust Building (33), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 59)
    - Riverside Drive Church (34), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 59)
    - Lower Manhattan Seen from Montague Terrace (35), 1931 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 59)
    - Metropolis from Governors Island (36), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 59)
    - Main Entrance - 18 Pine St. Chase National Bank (39), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 59)
    - Peacock Alley, Hotel Waldorf Astoria (40), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 59)
    - Interior [Equitable Trust Co., 11 Broad St.] (47), 1927 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 59)
    - Park Ave. Looking South from 64th St. (49), 1927 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 59)
    - The Plaza [Central Park Lake at 59th St.] (50), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 59)
    - St. Patrick's Cathedral (51), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 59)
    - Wall Street [illegible] (52), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 59)
    - Banking District (53), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 59)
    - Metropolis [from Governor's Island] (54), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 59)
    - Mid-town Manhattan Seen from Weehawken (55), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 59)
    - Madison Avenue Canyon (56), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 59)
    - [Times Square] (58), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 60)
    - The New Wall Street (59), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 60)
    - Towers of Mid-Manhattan Seen from Tudor City (60), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 60)
    - Three Towers Seen from 29th St. and Fifth Ave. (62), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 60)
    - Entrance Safe Deposit Vault, Equitable Trust Co., 11 Broad St. (63), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 60)
    - Wall St. 50 Years Ago (64), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 60)
    - Park Ave. seen from 55th St. Looking North (65), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 60)
    - Main Banking Floor, Equitable Trust Co., 11 Broad St. (66), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 60)
    - The Chase National Bank Building with NY Stock Exchange (67), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 60)
    - Seventh Ave. seen from Pennsylvania Roof (68), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 60)
    - The New Plaza Hotel Group seen from Central Park (69), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 60)
    - Fifth Avenue Looking South from 50th St. (70), 1927 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 60)
    - Queensborough Bridge at Sutton Place (71), 1927 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 60)
    - N.Y. Cotton Exchange seen from Broad St. (73), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 60)
    - The Three Giants: N.Y. Telephone Bldg, Woolworth and Transportation Bldgs (75), 1927 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 60)
    - Bowling Green seen from U.S. Custom House (76), 1927 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 61)
    - Equitable Trust Bldg. (77), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 61)
    - New York Stock Exchange (78), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 61)
    - New York City Court House [Foley Square] (79), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 61)
    - Brooklyn Bridge with New Downtown Sky Line (81), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 61)
    - [New York] Curb Exchange, looking west from Trinity Churchyard (82), 1930 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 61)
    - Gateway to Wall Street at Broadway (83), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 61)
    - Medical Center seen from the Hudson River bank at 165 St. (88), 1927 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 61)
    - [Medical Center, New York City] (89), 1927 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 61)
    - Broad Street Canyon (90), 1927 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 61)
    - The Heart of Brooklyn seen from the Brooklyn Daily Eagle Building (91), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 61)
    - New York Stock Exchange [from Wall Street] (93), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 61)
    - Four Bridges seen from 24th floor of 16 Court St., Brooklyn (95), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 61)
    - Grand Ballroom, Hotel Waldorf-Astoria, Fifth Ave. & 34th St. (96), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 61)
    - The New Bank of the Manhattan Company (98), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 61)
    - Guardian Life Bldg. [Union Square] (99), 1930 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 62)
    - Midtown Canyon (103), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 62)
    - George Washington Bridge, showing Manhattan approaches (104), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 62)
    - George Washington Bridge from New Jersey (105), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 62)
    - George Washington Bridge (106), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 62)
    - The Empire State Building seen from 29th Street and Hotel Seville, showing Little Church Around the Corner (108), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 62)
    - Plaza Lights, looking downtown from Central Park and 65th St. (110), 1931 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 62)
    - The Great White Way, looking towards Times Square, from 49th St. (111), 1931 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 62)
    - [Finchley Building] (264), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 62)
    - Union League Club at Fifth Ave. & 39th St. (265), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 62)
    - [Bridge in Central Park] (266), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 62)
    - [Manhattan Skyline] (267), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 62)
    - [Skyscrapers] (268), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 62)
    - [Exchange Place from Broadway] (269), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 62)
    - [Broad Street looking north from Beaver St.] (270), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 62)
    - Wall Street looking toward Trinity Church (271), 1926 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 63)
    - [Lower Manhattan from Governors Island] (272), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 63)
    - [Temple Emanu-El, 43rd St. and Fifth Ave.] (273), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 63)
    - [View from Bryant Park, 42nd Street and Sixth Avenue] (274), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 63)
    - Between the Islands [showing and ocean liner leaving New York Harbor, Statue of Liberty, Ellis Island, etc.] (275), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 63)
    - [Manhattan skyline] Seen from 2 Montague Terrace (276), 1931 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 63)
    - [Madison Square Garden] (277), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 63)
    - [New York Stock Exchange] (278), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 63)
    - [Broadway Canyon] (279), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 63)
    - [Ocean liner and lower Manhattan skyline from New Jersey shore] (280), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 63)
    - [Lower Manhattan skyline showing the East River from Governors Island] (281), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 63)
    - East River [from Governors Island] (282), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 63)
    - [S.S. Olympic and Manhattan skyline] (283), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 63)
    - [Manhattan skyline seen from 212 Columbia Heights] (284), 1925 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 63)
    - [S.S. Aquitania with Manhattan skyline] (285), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 63)
    - [S.S. Cleveland with Manhattan skyline] (286), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 64)
    - [S.S. Majestic with Manhattan skyline] (287), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 64)
    - [Banker's Trust Building] (288), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 64)
    - [Piers on the East River] (289), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 64)
    - [Whitehall Building from the water] (290), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 64)
    - [Grand Central Station looking east from Madison Avenue] (339), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 64)
    - [Corner of Fifth Ave. and Central Park (about 59th St.)] (340), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 64)
    - Oldest House in New York - West End Ave. and 95th St. (341), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 64)
    - Capital and Labor (342), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 64)
    - Broad Street Canyon - Equitable Trust Building seen from the 18th floor of the 50 Broad St. Building (343), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 64)
    - [Seventy-first Regiment Armory, showing building under construction south on Park Avenue] (344), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 64)
    - Two Bridges [view from Brooklyn toward Manhattan] (345), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 64)
    - Air Castle [lower Manhattan from Governor's Island] (346), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 64)
    - [Three bridges, view from lower Manhattan] (347), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 64)
    - Sky line of Brooklyn and East River Seen from Coenties Slip (348), 1927 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 64)
    - [42nd Street looking west from Sixth Avenue] (349), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - Broadway and Trinity Church looking north from Exchange Place (368), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - Lower Manhattan, from 2 Montague Terrace, Brooklyn Heights (369), 1931 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - [Woolworth Building, seen through arch of Municipal Building] (370), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - Brooklyn Bridge & Lower Manhattan (371), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - [Madison Square Garden] (372), 1925 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - [Trinity Church] (373), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - [Broadway from Battery Place] (374), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - Evening on the East River (375), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - [Waldorf-Astoria Hotel, Fifth Avenue and 34th Street] (376), 1929 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - Equitable Trust Building seen from the 19th floor of 5 Nassau St. (390), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - [Broadway, looking north from Bowling Green] (391), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - [Wall Street looking toward Trinity Church] (397), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - [Bowling Green looking north] (399), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - [Broadway looking south from Chambers Street] (403), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - [42nd Street looking west from Fifth Avenue] (422), 1927 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - [Pershing Square viaduct] (428), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - [King Manor House in Jamaica, NY] (435), 1926 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - [Two proofs from cancelled plates: Heckscher Building and Madison Square Garden, both printed on one sheet and inscribed to James Boyd, 19 Oct. 1925] (443), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 65)
    - Three Hundred Years of New York (New York Graphic Society) (445), 1926 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 66)
      Financial District
      City Hall, 1810
      Madison Square Garden, 1924
    - Three Hundred Years of New York (New York Graphic Society) (445), 1926 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 67)
      New York, 1690
      New York seen from Brooklyn Heights
      New York, 1675
    - Three Hundred Years of New York (New York Graphic Society) (445), 1926 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 68)
      New York, 1650
      Barge Office, 1850
      South Street, 1835
    - Three Hundred Years of New York (New York Graphic Society) (445), 1926 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 69)
      Wall Street, 1788
      Fort Jay at Governor's Island
      Broadway Bridge, 1870
    - Corner Broad and Exchange Sts. (471), 1927 (Offsite-box 4, Folder 70)
    - The Old Guard (Governor's Island, Fort Jay in the foreground) (472), undated (Offsite-box 4, Folder 70)
  - Simon, Tavik Frantisek (1877-1942)
    - New York Skyline (141), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 71)
  - Simonsen, Paul
    - South Street, NYC/Pier #12 (153), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 72)
    - 49th & 6th Ave., NYC (154), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 72)
    - 51st St. and Park Ave. N.Y.C. (155), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 72)
    - 59th & Lexington Avenue (156), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 72)
    - 5th & 54th Street (157), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 72)
    - Fulton & West Broadway (158), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 72)
    - 55th & Lexington (159), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 72)
    - Cedar & Nassau (160), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 72)
    - Broad & S William St. (161), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 72)
    - St. Thomas's [Protestant Episcopal Church] (162), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 73)
    - 42nd St @ 6th Ave., N.Y.C. (163), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 73)
    - Chapel of the Intercession, NYC (164), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 73)
    - Broad & S. William St., NYC (165), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 73)
    - Hotel Shelton, NYC (166), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 73)
    - William at Fulton St., NYC (167), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 73)
    - [Church of the] Heavenly Rest, NYC (168), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 73)
    - The Coal Dock, N.Y.C. (169), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 73)
  - Sloan, John (1871-1951)
    - Busses - Washington Square (258), 1925 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 74)
    - Snowstorm in the Village (259), 1925 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 74)
    - Sculpture in Washington Square (260), 1925 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 74)
    - Easter Eve, Washington Square (261), 1926 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 74)
    - Swinging in the Park (262), 1912 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 74)
    - Washington Arch (263), 1925 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 74)
  - Struck, Hermann
    - New York Skyline from Brooklyn (143), undated (Box Unknown container 299 for instance of New York Skyline from Brooklyn (143), Folder unknown container)
      See: Box 6, Folder 96
  - Suydam, E. H.
    - Wall Street with Trinity [Church] (500), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 75)
    - Cafe Mori [Bleecker St. and West Broadway] (501), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 75)
    - India House [Hanover Square] (502), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 75)
  - Szanto, Louis (b. 1889)
    - The Newspaper Boys in Wall Street (214), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 76)
    - Fifth Avenue at 42nd Street (331), 1929 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 76)
  - Trowbridge, V.
    - [Riverside Park] (442), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 77)
    - [Friends Meeting House, Stuyvesant Park] (395), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 77)
    - [Brooklyn Bridge] (396), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 77)
    - Madison Square Garden, NY, color (401), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 77)
  - Van Horne
    - [Washington Arch] (402), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 78)
  - Van Noth, H.
    - [Woolworth Bldg, St. Paul's Chapel] color (393), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 79)
  - W [?], Casimir
    - Wall Street, New York (191), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 80)
    - John Street, New York (192), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 80)
  - Wall, Bernhardt
    - [New York Harbor with Statue of Liberty] (309), 1916 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 81)
    - [The Aquarium] (310), 1920 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 81)
    - [St. Peter's Church, 31 Barclay St.] (441), 1924 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 81)
  - Wallace, William
    - Evening Post Building, corner of Nassau and Liberty (216), 1861 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 82)
    - Laura Keen[e]s - Broadway [near Prince Street] (217), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 82)
    - Niblo's Garden Theatre, rear on Crosby Street (218), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 82)
    - Corner of Pine St. and Broadway, 1820 (219), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 82)
    - The Canal, foot of Broad St. in Dutch times (220), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 82)
    - Ann St. Corner Theatre Alley (221), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 82)
    - The Grapevine Inn (222), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 82)
    - Wallack's Theatre, Fourth Ave. & 13th St. (223), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 82)
    - Broughams Lyceum, after first Wallack's Theatre, Broadway near Broom[e] (224), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 82)
    - 31 Bond St. [the Burdell house] (225), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 83)
    - Maiden Lane and Liberty Street (226), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 83)
    - Corner of Wall and Nassau St., 1856 (227), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 83)
    - Poe Cottage at Ford[h]am New York (228), 1880 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 83)
    - Ice in the Bay (229), 1882 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 83)
    - Poe's Cottage at Ford[h]am New York (230), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 83)
    - The Middle Dutch Church [about 1730] (231), 1882 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 83)
    - Bradburn's Book Stall, cor. Fulton and Nassau St. (233), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 83)
    - New York from Brooklyn (250), 1880 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 83)
  - Ward, William
    - East River at 42nd Street (137), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 84)
    - Fifth Avenue and 42nd Street (138), 1931 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 84)
    - West 42nd St. Ferry (247), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 84)
  - Webster, Herman A.
    - [Cortlandt Street] (324), 1910 (Offsite-box 5, Folder 85)
  - Welsh, Devitt
    - [New York Life Insurance Building] (170), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 86)
    - [Brooklyn Bridge] (171), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 86)
    - [New York Stock Exchange] (172), undated (Offsite-box 5, Folder 86)